Life is amazing.
生命是惊人的。
Life is incredible.
生命是令人难以置信的。
The experience is we have the possibilities of personal achievement.
经验是,我们有可能取得个人成就。
You could summon that Everest.
你可以召唤那个珠穆朗玛峰
You could create a huge successful business.
你可以创造 巨大的成功业务。
You could give a TED talk.
你可以给TED演讲。
And when you're successful, it feels incredible.
当你成功的时候 感觉不可思议
Success, the flush of excitement, the celebration,
成功,兴奋的冲浪, 庆祝,
and you should celebrate the congratulations, the posting on Instagram,
并且你应该庆祝 祝贺, 张贴在Instagram,
wherever you put your stuff up, it all feels great.
不论你把东西放在哪里,都感觉很好。
But when that fades and that starts to fade,
但当它消逝时,它开始消退,
sometimes slowly, sometimes all at once, a question comes up.
有时是缓慢的,有时是同时发生的, 出现一个问题。
Is this it? Is this all there is?
就这些吗?
And so I'm going to tell you a little story about myself to give you sense of this.
所以我要告诉你一个小故事 关于我自己的故事 给你这个感觉。
So if those of you don't know what Professor is, Stanford,
所以如果你们这些人不知道 斯坦福教授是什么
I got my job, I was elated and elated.
我得到了我的工作, 我高兴和高兴。
And a little bit terrified.
有点吓坏了
Now, it's terrified because when you get up job like that,
现在,它被吓坏了,因为当你 得到这样的工作,
you know you're going to be reviewed in about seven years.
你知道你将在七年后接受审查
And either you're going to give in ten years more or less a job for life,
要么你再多给十年时间 要么就给一份终身工作
or you're going to get fired.
否则你会被炒鱿鱼的
It's a little bit like that movie, Glenn Gary Glenn Ross.
有点像那部电影 格伦·盖瑞·格伦·罗斯
The scene where Alec Baldwin's character goes in to give the motivational speech,
Alec Baldwin的性格 用来进行激励性演讲的场景
and he says, it's going to be a competition.
他说,这将是一场比赛。
First prize, Cadillac Alderado.
一等奖,凯迪拉克・阿尔德拉多
Second prize, set of steak knives.
二等奖,一套牛排刀
Third prize, you're fired.
三等奖,你被解雇了
It's a little bit like that except there's no second prize.
有点像,除了没有二等奖
And it turns out, as you might imagine, that has a way of focusing your mind.
结果,正如你可能想象的那样, 这可以让你的头脑集中起来。
And it's always really, really focused on doing good research.
并且它总是真正,真的 专注于 做良好的研究。
Give my papers published, doing on the classroom, and all the other little things you need to do to get tenure.
把我的论文发表在课堂上 以及你为了获得终身职位 需要做的其他小事 都交给我
And seven years later, I made it.
七年后,我成功了
I made it.
我办到了 I made it.
Thank you.
谢谢
And it was a huge relief.
这是一个巨大的解脱。
And I was so excited.
我太激动了
I was so excited.
But that question came up.
但是,出现了这个问题。
Is this really all there is?
真的就只有这些吗?
And I reflected back, and I thought about the Thomas Denton undergrad five years in grad school.
我反省了一下, 我想到了托马斯·丹顿五年级的研究生。
The tears, and there were a lot of tears.
眼泪, 和有很多眼泪。
The seven years of trying to get tenure, and I had expected.
试图获得任期的七年, 我早就料到了。
I had hoped that when I made it past that, when I succeeded, when I went through that threshold,
我曾经希望 当我过去,当我成功, 当我走过那个门槛,
life would feel different.
生活会感觉不同
I would feel fulfilled.
我会感到满足。
It would feel meaningful to me.
这会让我感觉有意义
My life would feel meaningful.
我的生活会感觉有意义
But it turns out that wasn't what happened.
但事实却并非如此。
Now, when psychologists talk about meaningfulness in life, what they're talking about is a sense that our lives matter.
现在,当心理学家谈论生活中的意义时, 他们所谈论的就是我们生命的意义。
That the world makes sense.
这世界是有道理的。
That we are more than the sum of our minutes, days, and years on this planet.
我们不仅仅是我们在这个星球上的 时间、时间和年数的总和。
Now, the research on meaningfulness in life suggests that there are three big ideas associated with meaningfulness in life.
现在,关于生命中有意义的研究 表明,生命中有三个大概念 与生命中的有意义的有关。
The first big idea is coherence.
第一个大想法是一致性。
The world needs to feel coherent.
世界需要感到协调一致。
After winter comes spring, after spring comes summer, you get up in the morning, you brush your teeth, you have breakfast, you get the kids off,
冬天过后春天,春天过后夏天, 你早上起床,刷牙,吃早餐,让孩子们下车,
you go to work, those little routines make the world feel noable, predictable.
你去工作,这些小的例行公事 让世界感到无名可言,可以预测
Coherent.
步调一致
Now, when you think about personal achievement, it does create sometimes this experience of coherence because we achieve within a framework.
现在,当你考虑个人成就时,它确实有时创造出这种一致性的经验,因为我们在一个框架内实现。
I understood what they expected of me for 10 years.
我理解他们10年来对我的期望。
I understood that if I got my papers published, that did well in the classroom, that I talked to the right people, that all the networking, that was a good chance I could tenure.
我理解,如果我的论文出版, 在课堂上做得很好, 我和正确的人交谈, 所有网络, 这是一个很好的机会 我可以使用。
If you're trying to lose weight, you understand.
如果你想减肥,你明白的
If you change your diet, you exercise.
如果你改变饮食,你运动。
The weight will come off, or at least we hope so.
重量会下降,至少我们希望如此。
Now, those things that framework gives the world a sense of coherence.
现在,那些框架赋予世界一种一致性感的东西。
Second big idea associated with meaningfulness in life, second big idea.
第二个大点子 与生活中的有意义有关,第二个大点子。
Purpose.
目的。
Now, sometimes people use the term purpose as a synonym for meaning in life, and that's not how I mean it here.
有时候人们用这个词来形容生命的意义, 而不是我在这里的意思。
Purpose is a way of thinking about what your life can be and should be in the future.
目的就是思考你的生活 将来会是什么样的 将来会是什么样的
It's a way of directing your actions.
这是指导你行动的一种方式
It gives you goals.
它给了你目标。
When you get up in the morning, you know what you need to do.
当你早上起床时 你知道你需要做什么
Here's where the drive for personal achievement is strongest.
这是个人成就最强劲的动力
It's clearest.
这是最清楚的。
When I was worried about 10 year-end, you were exactly what I need to do when I got up in the morning.
当我担心十岁大的时候 你正是我早上起床时 需要做的
When you have a goal, when you're trying to achieve something, you have a clarity about what you should do, how to direct your behavior.
当你有一个目标, 当你试图实现某事, 你清楚你应该做什么, 如何指导你的行为。
So that's the second big idea is purpose.
所以这是第二个大想法是目的。
Now, the third big idea by many considered to be the most important is significance.
现在,许多人认为最重要的第三个大想法是意义。
The way I like to think about significance is the sense that you can transcend yourself.
我喜欢思考意义的方式是 感觉你可以超越自己。
That you are more than what you are right now, but you will continue to matter into the future beyond this moment.
你不只是现在的你, 但你会继续关注未来, 在这个时刻之后。
This is where I think personal achievement falls short.
这就是我认为个人成就不足的地方。
But definition personal achievement focuses on you.
但定义个人成就的重点放在你身上。
It's a focus on the self.
这是对自我的专注
If that's all there is, it's difficult to have significance.
如果仅此而已 意义就很难了
So now I want to think about meaningfulness in life.
所以我现在想思考生活中的意义。
And significance in particular, it brings to mind a quote attributed to Leonardo da Vinci.
尤其重要的是,它引出了莱昂纳多·达芬奇的引文。
Some of you might know it.
你们中有些人可能知道
So Leonardo da Vinci was, purported to have said on his deathbed,
So Leonardo da Vinci在临终前说
I have offended God and mankind because my work did not achieve the quality of life.
我冒犯了上帝和人类,因为我的工作没有达到生活质量。
Now, I wasn't there.
现在,我不在那里。
So I don't know if he said that exactly in that way.
所以我不知道他是不是这么说的
But here's the thing, you can imagine it.
但事情是这样的,你可以想象
You understand it.
你明白这一点。
You understand what it means to have even the most glorious achievements and still ask,
你明白获得甚至最光荣的成就意味着什么,你仍然在问:
Is this enough?
够了吗?
Is this it?
是这个吗?
Is this all I had up to?
这就是我所要做的事吗?
When I look back and think about my time, early on in my career,
当我回首往事 思考我的时代 早年我的职业生涯
I think about when did it feel meaningful?
我想到什么时候感觉有意义了?
What gave me a sense of meaning?
是什么给了我一种意义感?
What I think about were my PhD students.
我想到的是我的博士生
So one of the things that faculty do is train the next generation of faculty.
所以教职员工做的一件事 就是训练下一代教职员工。
And so you have PhD students and you have them for significant amount of time.
所以,你有博士生 和你有他们 相当长的时间。
Often, it could be five to six years.
通常,可能要5至6年。
And the relationships are pretty intense.
关系非常紧张
So let me tell you about my first student, Miguel Lensway to him.
让我来告诉你我的第一个学生 Miguel Lensway的事
So Miguel, I was born in El Paso, Texas,
米格尔,我出生在德州埃尔帕索
and the relatively low income area.
以及相对低收入地区。
Really smart kid does well in school.
聪明的孩子在学校表现很好
It ends up at the University of Texas at Austin, which is a great university.
最终在奥斯汀的得克萨斯大学 一所很棒的大学
Does well there eventually ends up in the PhD program at Stanford.
最终会进入斯坦福的博士学位课程
So Miguel gets there the year before I do.
所以Miguel比我早一年到达那里
And by his own account, he's having a tough time.
以他自己的名号来看 他正经历着艰难的时光
It's a little rough.
有点粗糙
And it's rough in part because he doesn't have the cultural capital that many people
部分是因为他没有 很多人拥有的文化资本
They go places like Stanford have.
他们去像斯坦福一样的地方
He doesn't understand how the place works.
他不明白这个地方是怎么运作的
So he's struggling a little bit.
所以他有点挣扎
Now when I arrive, I'm really impressed because he's so smart.
现在当我到了,我真的印象深刻 因为他是如此聪明。
He's ambitious.
他很雄心勃勃
And he's asking questions and interested in things that I'm interested in.
他在问问题 对我感兴趣的事情感兴趣
So I'm really excited to work with him.
所以我很兴奋能和他一起工作
And so we started to work together.
于是我们开始合作。
And again, it's really intense.
再说一遍,它真的很强烈。
I'm working with him for four years.
我和他共事四年
We see each other almost every day, almost every day for those four years.
在这四年里,我们几乎每天都在见面,几乎每天都在见面。
And some days we're working together 10 to 12 hours a day.
有时候我们一天工作10到12小时
So it's a very intense experience.
所以这是一个非常激烈的经历。
And what I remember about that time was that I was really worried about.
我记得关于那段时间, 我非常担心。
Doing enough to make sure he would be successful.
足以确保他取得成功。
I was concerned.
我当时很担心
Am I being a good advisor?
我是好顾问吗?
Am I giving him what he needs?
我给他他需要的东西了吗?
Am I helping him in his story?
我在帮他写故事吗?
Now keep in mind, I want to get tenure.
现在记住,我想获得任期。
I still think I'm going to get fired.
我还是认为我会被炒鱿鱼
So even with that fear, I'm worried about what do I need to do to make sure Miguel can continue
所以即使有这种恐惧 我也很担心我需要做些什么 确保米格尔能继续
in his story and his journey.
他的故事和历程。
And by the way, he did see.
顺便说一句,他确实看到了。
He's been great.
他是伟大的。
He got a job.
他找到了一份工作。
He's been a professor now for over 15 years at UCLA.
他现在在加州大学洛杉矶分校当教授超过15年了
He's had serious leadership roles at his university.
他在他的大学里 扮演过严肃的领导角色
And I'm incredibly proud that I got to chance to be a little part of that.
我感到非常自豪 我有机会参与其中
What does it take from that?
这有什么意义?
What I take from that is that relationships are what provide us meaning.
我从中得出这样的结论,即关系为我们提供了意义。
And my guess is you already knew that.
我猜你已经知道了
I'm saying something a little bit more than that.
我说的不止这些
Not just that relationships provide meaning, but the being a part of a story that is not your role.
不仅这种关系提供了意义, 而且是故事的一部分, 而不是你的角色。
That is not your own provides meaning.
这不是你自己赋予的含义。
Being a part of a story that is not your own provides meaning.
成为故事的一部分 不是你自己的 提供意义。
So what does this leave us?
那么,这给我们留下了什么?
One, I think personal achievement is great.
第一,我认为个人成就是巨大的。
I love my personal achievements.
我喜欢我个人的成就。
I'm really happy with my life.
我对我的生活真的很满意
I think it's turned out okay.
我觉得结果还不错
I wish incredible personal achievements for all of you.
我祝愿大家个人取得令人难以置信的成就。
So I think that personal achievement is fantastic.
因此,我认为,个人的成就是惊人的。
However, sometimes we replace the deep human need for meaning with chasing of personal achievement.
然而,有时我们用追求个人成就来取代人类对意义的巨大需要。
And it's a problem when we confuse those two things.
当我们混淆这两件事时,这是个问题。
And the reason they get confused, the reason it's easy to confuse them is because personal achievement is easy to quantify.
他们困惑的原因 容易混淆的原因是 个人成就很容易量化
You know if you got that job, you know if you bought that home.
你知道,如果你得到了那份工作, 你知道,如果你买了那家。
You know how you're with your salary. It's easy to see.
你知道你薪水多高 很容易看出来
And it's feels comfortable to chase things you understand.
追逐你所理解的事情 感觉很舒服
And you can achieve. That's one reason.
你可以达到目的,这是原因之一
The other reason is that personal achievement feels good.
另一个原因是个人成就感觉良好。
Personal achievement feels good.
个人成就感觉良好。
We want this happiness.
我们希望这种幸福。
And personal achievement provides a hit of happiness.
个人成就是幸福的一击。
It feels fantastic when you make that person that achievement.
当你让那个人取得成就时 感觉棒极了
Getting meaning doesn't necessarily feel that way.
获得意义不一定有这种感觉。
For example, studies find that parents who spend more time parenting their children, report more meaningful in life,
例如,研究发现,父母为子女做父母的时间越长,其报告在生活中就越有意义,
but not necessarily more happiness.
但不一定是更多的快乐。
So these things are not the same.
所以,这些事情是不一样的。
So if you want more meaning in life, what is there to do?
所以,如果你想在生活中有更大的意义, 还有什么可以做的呢?
One, look for opportunities to participate in other stories.
第一,寻找参与其他故事的机会。
Like a lot of us, you know, it's funny.
就像我们很多人,你知道,这很有趣。
I'm saying this is outstanding on the stage in the circle.
我的意思是,这是杰出的 在舞台上的圆圈。
But there's a lot of main character energy I would argue in this room right now.
但我现在在这个房间里 有很多主要的性格能量
Just fantastic. I love it.
棒极了,我爱死它了
However, you might try a little supporting actor energy if you want meaning.
但是,如果你想要意义的话,你可以尝试一点支持演员的能量。
Play a supporting role in other people's lives.
在他人生活中发挥辅助作用。
That's number one.
这是第一。
Two, except that the pursuit of meaning may not generate happiness.
第二,除了追求意义 可能不会带来幸福。
In fact, it might be uncomfortable that turns out that meaning is more associated with the self-providing for others than providing for you, for yourself.
事实上,也许令人不自在的是 意思更多地与他人的自我供给有关 而不是为您,为您自己提供。
And that's sometimes a hard thing to do.
有时候这很难做到
Expending effort, emotional energy on behalf of something that is not going to return happiness is not something that we tend to think of as a useful, a good use of our time.
我们往往认为,为了一些不会带来幸福的东西而付出的巨大努力、情感能量,并不是一个有益、很好地利用我们时代的东西。
But it turns out it does produce meaning.
但事实证明,它确实产生了意义。
So let me say just a couple more things.
所以,让我再说几句话。
One, I think the human need and pursuit of meaning is both beautiful and profound because when you have meaning in your life, that means that someone else gave you the opportunity to participate in the story that is not your own.
第一,我认为人类需要和追求意义是既美丽又深刻的,因为当你在生活中有意义时,这意味着其他人给了你机会,参与不属于你的故事。
And for that, for the meaning you have in your life, you should feel a deep gratitude, a deep gratitude for the people who have allowed you to participate in the story that was not your own.
为此,从你一生的意义来看, 你应该深深的感激, 深深的感激那些 让你参与这个故事的人, 而不是你自己的故事。
On the other side, when you allow people to participate in your life, you're giving them the opportunity to generate meaning.
另一方面,当你允许人们参与你的生活时, 你给他们创造意义的机会。
And so in that way, the deep human need for meaning connects us in a circle.
因此,通过这种方式, 人类对含义的深刻需求 把我们连接在一个圆圈里。
I think a beautiful and profound circle of generosity and gratitude.
我认为,慷慨和感激的循环是美丽和深刻的。
And so right now here, I'm deeply grateful that you all have let me participate in your stories.
所以,现在在这里,我深深地感谢 你们都让我参与你们的故事。
And that's deeply mean for me. Thank you for that.
这对我太刻薄了 谢谢你
The theme of this conference is the brave and the brilliant.
本次会议的主题是勇敢和辉煌。
I think that one way that we can experience or be brave is by accepting the fact that our personal achievements, what we're capable of, what things that we've done, pale, pale, and comparison.
我认为,一个我们可以体验或勇敢的方法 就是接受这样的事实 我们的个人成就,我们的能力, 我们所做的一切, 苍白,苍白, 和比较。
So the effect we have on other people and what that does in the world.
因此,我们对其他人的影响 以及这世界上发生的事情。
And that is you go through the world with all of your brilliance.
那就是你带着你所有的才华 环游世界
And that means that in terms of light, as you go through the world, lighting the world, when you interact with other people,
这意味着,从光的角度来看, 当你走遍世界, 照亮世界, 当你与其他人互动,
and you illuminate them and help them shine more brightly, that's how the world gets illuminated.
你照亮他们,帮助他们更亮亮亮, 这就是世界如何被照亮。
That's how we bring up the lights. And the world obviously desperately needs that.
我们就是这样把灯亮起来的 全世界显然急需灯光
And in return, what you get is meaning because when we're gone, all of the accomplishments will mean nothing, the only thing that will be left of you when you're gone.
作为回报,你得到的是意义 因为当我们走了, 所有的成就将毫无意义, 当你离开时,你唯一会留下的东西。
And we all will be gone eventually. The only thing will be left of you is the role you played in other people's stories.
我们最终都会消失。唯一剩下的就是你在别人的故事中扮演的角色。
What you leave with other people, how that reverberates through time.
你留给别人的东西, 和它如何在时间上回响。
And that is a beautiful thing, and I wish all of that for you. Thank you.
这是一件美丽的事情,我希望所有这一切都为你。谢谢。